<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Samuele Bella</title><link>https://novaenn.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Samuele Bella</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Samuele Bella</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 19:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novaenn.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On liking a lot of different things</title><link>https://novaenn.github.io/posts/onlikingstuff/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://novaenn.github.io/posts/onlikingstuff/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post will talk about my thoughts on having multiple interests and having the time to satisfy them.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post will talk about my thoughts on having multiple interests and having the time to satisfy them.</p>
<p>Lately, I became really interested in multiple subjects which were very far conceptually from Computer Science, my current field of study.
Some of them were <em>probably</em> caused by me having a crush on a girl who had knowledge ranging from the more scientific subjects like mathematics to more humanistic fields like <a href="https://iai.tv/articles/the-courage-to-face-a-lifetime-on-the-enduring-value-of-ayn-rands-philosophy-auid-846">philosophy</a>, <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/06/08/edward-hopper-and-american-solitude?utm_source=pocket_saves">art</a> and <a href="https://www.theschooloflife.com/article/what-is-literature-for-3/">literature</a>. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
(I explain more deeply about how I exploit to my advantage crushes that may or may not be successful in the post <a href="/posts/on-attraction-having-a-crush-and-limerence/">&ldquo;On attraction, having a crush and Limerence&rdquo;</a>).</p>
<h2 id="what-caused-the-rambling">What caused the rambling</h2>
<p>Recently I stumbled upon a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nu2T1_rbF1s">video</a> from R.C. Waldun that introduced the idea of being a <em><strong>Multipotentialite</strong></em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A multipotentialite is a person who has many different interests and creative pursuits in life.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I usually pick up a skill or subject I&rsquo;m interested in, and then, after having reached my desired &ldquo;skill level&rdquo;, I lose interest and move on to another topic. Has something similar ever happened to you?</p>
<h2 id="the-problem">The &ldquo;Problem&rdquo;</h2>
<p>So you might ask: &ldquo;What&rsquo;s wrong with liking different stuff? Isn&rsquo;t it amazing to be constantly fascinated by random things, serendipity on your side and all?&rdquo;. Well, it&rsquo;s a bit more complicated than that.</p>
<p>While having a quasi-infinite bucket list of things to learn and explore is indeed terrific, finding the time to pursue those interests <em>is</em> less so. In these months the number of my interests has greatly increased, which isn&rsquo;t great since I&rsquo;m in the middle of exam sessions.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/84456037-samuele">Books</a> are usually the culprit, but <a href="https://weeklymusings.net/">blogs</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P1PC1sArw70&amp;list=PLO17mUvu8KA1IxHXLcoKtpGrfuPI0THu9&amp;index=1&amp;t=404s">videos</a> play a part in it as well.</p>
<p>I occasionally fail to balance other important things in life such as studying for exams, nurturing social relationships, and getting some entertainment in order to pursue whatever I encountered by happenstance.</p>
<h2 id="how-i-solve-it">How I solve it</h2>
<p>To combat my never ending supply of procrastination I force myself to respect a strict schedule everytime I need to prepare for an exam or when I have other important tasks to handle.
I like to mix <a href="https://calendar.google.com/">Google Calendar</a> and <a href="https://todoist.com/">Todoist</a> to sort my short and long-term goals.
I create events in GCal to organize and not forget every type of event I have to attend and use Todoist to create a to-do list ordered by priority for the things that I have to accomplish during the day.<br>
With this method, I consistently manage to finish my important daily tasks and satisfy my curiosity without sacrificing one or the other.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>To conclude, I advise everyone to pursue every single thing that they are passionate about. When you encounter something remotely interesting, I suggest throwing yourself into it (if you have time, of course) and seeing where it leads, you might be surprised by the number of interesting things that we ignore daily.</p>]]></content></item><item><title>On studying and the role of educational institutions</title><link>https://novaenn.github.io/posts/on-studying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 20:46:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://novaenn.github.io/posts/on-studying/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post will talk about my thoughts concerning knowledge, the act of studying, and the role of educational institutions in this topic.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post will talk about my thoughts concerning knowledge, the act of studying, and the role of educational institutions in this topic.</p>
    <img src="peanuts-library-card.png"  alt="Peanuts"  class="center"  />


<h2 id="what-caused-the-rambling">What caused the rambling</h2>
<p>Since the third year of High School, I started thinking about the relationship between studying, schools, and professors. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Are schools and universities necessary to gain knowledge, or is studying also an individual act? What about professors? What&rsquo;s their role? Is their job only to teach their assigned subject or do they serve a broader and more noble purpose? Let&rsquo;s think about it.</p>
<h2 id="so-what-about-schools-and-universities">So, what about schools and universities?</h2>
<p>The concept of university was and still is very exciting to me.
I can attend classes of stuff that interests me while being taught by professors who have been studying that same topic for years of their life, sounds like paradise right? Eh, let&rsquo;s discuss about it.</p>
<p>Even though the majority of the professors that I&rsquo;ve been lectured by were deeply passionate, unfortunately, the small minority of those who were treating their course lackadaisically or those who were so obsessed with the topic they&rsquo;ve been researching that nothing else matters kinda spoiled my experience.
I am filled with sorrow when I attend a lecture by a professor who isn&rsquo;t passionate about the content of his teachings. We, the students, don&rsquo;t receive a top-notch education and the teacher doesn&rsquo;t feel satisfied with his job, it&rsquo;s a loss for everyone.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s obvious that no one&rsquo;s at fault here, we can&rsquo;t choose our teachers and they can&rsquo;t usually choose what course they&rsquo;ll be teaching. Usually, this issue arises when universities have courses with no professor and someone needs to be called to fill in. However, I&rsquo;m pretty sure that the solution is way more complex and harder to grasp.</p>
<h2 id="on-studying-for-professors-and-grades">On studying (for professors and grades)</h2>
<p>I will be probably <strong><em>very</em></strong> biased since I recently flunked an exam (Databases Module 2) for the third time in a row. However, I&rsquo;ll try my best to have an impartial view on this topic.</p>
<p>For starters, I absolutely despise myself every time I have to study for an exam that I have no interest in whatsoever. The thought of having to waste multiple hours memorizing concepts just to pass a test and then forgetting those same concepts two weeks after is unnerving (and don&rsquo;t get me started on professors that are probably direct descendants of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Narcissus_(mythology)">Narcissus</a>, they are deeply convinced that their course is the most important one and make it extremely hard to pass for no reason at all, looking at you TM).</p>
<p>In fact, I&rsquo;d rather be learning about some obscure topic that has no direct correlation to my field of study but interests me than waste time on something that I will probably never use again.</p>
<p>(That wasn&rsquo;t very impartial and unbiased huh?)</p>
<p>Finding a solution isn&rsquo;t simple and I&rsquo;m still struggling to conceive one that satisfies me. If you&rsquo;re a student currently enrolled in a university or college you might be aware of the fact that you must pass some mandatory courses at all costs in order to stay on track to get your so desired degree. You should also be aware of the fact that it&rsquo;s impossible to be interested in every single topic of your degree course.</p>
<h2 id="on-studying-for-me-myself-and-i">On studying (for me, myself and I)</h2>
<p>At last, let&rsquo;s talk about studying for the sake of studying.
While studying for a degree is useful for your career and your future, studying random stuff that has a high chance of being completely useless has a distinct charm and purpose to it.
It&rsquo;s fascinating how I can feel zero interest in an important topic for my career but feel high levels of engagement in subjects like <a href="https://iai.tv/articles/the-courage-to-face-a-lifetime-on-the-enduring-value-of-ayn-rands-philosophy-auid-846">philosophy</a>, <a href="https://thepointmag.com/examined-life/art-is-for-seeing-evil/">politics</a> and <a href="https://thepointmag.com/examined-life/art-is-for-seeing-evil/">art</a> <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/06/08/edward-hopper-and-american-solitude?utm_source=pocket_saves">[2]</a>.
I talk more about this weird concept in my post <a href="/posts/on-liking-a-lot-of-different-things/">&ldquo;On liking a lot of different things&rdquo;</a></p>
<p>When I was younger, however, I had conflicting feelings about these &ldquo;serendipitous&rdquo; interests and dismissed them as a waste of time, something that had the risk of distancing me from my future goals and ambitions. This is, unfortunately, a common thought among people my age.
Studying or, more precisely, gaining more knowledge, is seen as something superfluous, a waste of time, something that must necessarily be linked to your future job and be useful in order to find the job of your dreams (or whatever).</p>
<h2 id="small-thoughts-on-chaffeur-knowledge">Small thoughts on &ldquo;Chaffeur Knowledge&rdquo;</h2>
<p>I just read a <a href="https://perell.com/essay/how-philosophers-think/">great essay</a> which introduced to me Charlie Munger&rsquo;s distinction between &ldquo;real knowledge&rdquo; and &ldquo;chaffeur knowledge&rdquo;.
Real knowledge is when you take an idea and you embrace it, let it become a part of yourself, decompose it into its atoms while Chaffeur knowledge is just memorizing it and repeating it verbatim.
There&rsquo;s a really interesting quote in that essay that reads:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more pressure people feel to have an opinion on every subject, the more chauffeur knowledge there will be. In that state of intellectual insecurity, people rush to judgment. When they do, they abandon the philosophical mode of thinking. In turn, they become slaves to fashionable ideas and blind to unconscious assumptions.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I admit it, sometimes I fell into the trap of chaffeur thinking but I am really trying hard to overcome it. I prefer having a clear understanding of a few topics than little to no understanding of a whole variety of topics.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>To conclude, I think that studying isn&rsquo;t something that must be correlated to your precise field of study, and I don&rsquo;t think that it must be necessarily useful for your job.
Gaining knowledge for the sake of it is useful not only because it&rsquo;s fun, but also because it broadens your views and gives you an enormous sense of accomplishment.
However, you&rsquo;ll feel accomplished only if you really tackle the idea at hand, when you are sure to understand it completely. Don&rsquo;t be content with just Chaffeur knowledge.</p>
<p>Sapere aude.</p>]]></content></item></channel></rss>